A Guide to the Militia Commission Papers, 1777-1858
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Militia Commissions, 1777-1858., Extent: 66.71 cu. ft. (169 boxes). (Box 3-171)
  - Subseries B. Cities, 1777-1858.
    - Lynchburg, 1809. (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - Lynchburg, 1810. (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - Lynchburg, 1813. (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - Lynchburg, 1816. (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - Lynchburg, 1817. (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - Lynchburg, 1818. (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Lynchburg, 1819. (Box 162, Folder 9)
    - Lynchburg, 1820. (Box 162, Folder 10)
    - Lynchburg, 1821. (Box 162, Folder 11)
    - Lynchburg, 1822. (Box 162, Folder 12)
    - Lynchburg, 1823. (Box 162, Folder 13)
    - Lynchburg, 1824. (Box 162, Folder 14)
    - Lynchburg, 1825. (Box 162, Folder 15)
    - Lynchburg, 1826. (Box 162, Folder 16)
    - Lynchburg, 1827. (Box 162, Folder 17)
    - Lynchburg, 1828. (Box 162, Folder 18)
    - Lynchburg, 1829. (Box 162, Folder 19)
    - Lynchburg, 1830. (Box 162, Folder 20)
    - Lynchburg, 1831. (Box 162, Folder 21)
    - Lynchburg, 1832. (Box 162, Folder 22)
    - Lynchburg, 1833. (Box 162, Folder 23)
    - Lynchburg, 1834. (Box 162, Folder 24)
    - Lynchburg, 1835. (Box 162, Folder 25)
    - Lynchburg, 1836. (Box 162, Folder 26)
    - Lynchburg, 1837. (Box 162, Folder 27)
    - Lynchburg, 1838. (Box 162, Folder 28)
    - Lynchburg, 1839. (Box 162, Folder 29)
    - Lynchburg, 1840. (Box 162, Folder 30)
    - Lynchburg, 1841. (Box 162, Folder 31)
    - Lynchburg, 1842. (Box 162, Folder 32)
    - Lynchburg, 1843. (Box 162, Folder 33)
    - Lynchburg, 1844. (Box 162, Folder 34)
    - Lynchburg, 1845. (Box 162, Folder 35)
    - Lynchburg, 1846. (Box 162, Folder 36)
    - Lynchburg, 1847. (Box 162, Folder 37)
    - Lynchburg, 1848. (Box 162, Folder 38)
    - Lynchburg, 1849. (Box 162, Folder 39)
    - Lynchburg, 1850. (Box 162, Folder 40)
    - Lynchburg, 1851. (Box 162, Folder 41)
    - Lynchburg, 1852. (Box 162, Folder 42)
    - Lynchburg, 1853. (Box 162, Folder 43)
    - Lynchburg, undated. (Box 162, Folder 44)
    - Norfolk, 1781. (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk, 1782. (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk, 1783. (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk, 1784. (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Norfolk, 1785. (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk, 1787. (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - Norfolk, 1788. (Box 163, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk, 1790. (Box 163, Folder 8)
    - Norfolk, 1791. (Box 163, Folder 9)
    - Norfolk, 1792. (Box 163, Folder 10)
    - Norfolk, 1793. (Box 163, Folder 11)
    - Norfolk, 1794. (Box 163, Folder 12)
    - Norfolk, 1795. (Box 163, Folder 13)
    - Norfolk, 1796. (Box 163, Folder 14)
    - Norfolk, 1797. (Box 163, Folder 15)
    - Norfolk, 1798. (Box 163, Folder 16)
    - Norfolk, 1799. (Box 163, Folder 17)
    - Norfolk, 1800. (Box 163, Folder 18)
    - Norfolk, 1801. (Box 163, Folder 19)
    - Norfolk, 1802. (Box 163, Folder 20)
    - Norfolk, 1803. (Box 163, Folder 21)
    - Norfolk, 1804. (Box 163, Folder 22)
    - Norfolk, 1805. (Box 163, Folder 23)
    - Norfolk, 1806. (Box 163, Folder 24)
    - Norfolk, 1807. (Box 163, Folder 25)
    - Norfolk, 1808. (Box 163, Folder 26)
    - Norfolk, 1809. (Box 163, Folder 27)
    - Norfolk, 1810. (Box 163, Folder 28)
    - Norfolk, 1811. (Box 163, Folder 29)
    - Norfolk, 1812. (Box 163, Folder 30)
    - Norfolk, 1813. (Box 163, Folder 31)
    - Norfolk, 1814. (Box 163, Folder 32)
    - Norfolk, 1815. (Box 163, Folder 33)
    - Norfolk, 1816. (Box 163, Folder 34)
    - Norfolk, 1817. (Box 163, Folder 35)
    - Norfolk, 1818. (Box 163, Folder 36)
    - Norfolk, 1819. (Box 163, Folder 37)
    - Norfolk, 1820. (Box 163, Folder 38)
    - Norfolk, 1821. (Box 163, Folder 39)
    - Norfolk, 1822. (Box 163, Folder 40)
    - Norfolk, 1823. (Box 163, Folder 41)
    - Norfolk, 1824. (Box 163, Folder 42)
    - Norfolk, 1825. (Box 163, Folder 43)
    - Norfolk, 1826. (Box 163, Folder 44)
    - Norfolk, 1827. (Box 163, Folder 45)
    - Norfolk, 1828. (Box 163, Folder 46)
    - Norfolk, 1829. (Box 163, Folder 47)
    - Norfolk, 1830. (Box 163, Folder 48)
    - Norfolk, 1831. (Box 163, Folder 49)
    - Norfolk, 1832. (Box 163, Folder 50)
    - Norfolk, 1833. (Box 163, Folder 51)
    - Norfolk, 1834. (Box 163, Folder 52)
    - Norfolk, 1835. (Box 163, Folder 53)
    - Norfolk, 1836. (Box 163, Folder 54)
    - Norfolk, 1837. (Box 163, Folder 55)
    - Norfolk, 1838. (Box 163, Folder 56)
    - Norfolk, 1839. (Box 163, Folder 57)
    - Norfolk, 1840. (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk, 1841. (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk, 1842. (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk, 1843. (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Norfolk, 1844. (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk, 1845. (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - Norfolk, 1846. (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk, 1847. (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - Norfolk, 1848. (Box 164, Folder 9)
    - Norfolk, 1849. (Box 164, Folder 10)
    - Norfolk, 1850. (Box 164, Folder 11)
    - Norfolk, 1851. (Box 164, Folder 12)
    - Norfolk, 1852. (Box 164, Folder 13)
    - Norfolk, 1854. (Box 164, Folder 14)
    - Norfolk, 1855. (Box 164, Folder 15)
    - Norfolk, 1856. (Box 164, Folder 16)
    - Norfolk, 1857. (Box 164, Folder 17)
    - Norfolk, no date. (Box 164, Folder 18)
    - Petersburg, 1797. (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - Petersburg, 1798. (Box 165, Folder 2)
    - Petersburg, 1805. (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - Petersburg, 1806. (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Petersburg, 1807. (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Petersburg, 1808. (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - Petersburg, 1809. (Box 165, Folder 7)
    - Petersburg, 1812. (Box 165, Folder 8)
    - Petersburg, 1816. (Box 165, Folder 9)
    - Petersburg, 1818. (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Petersburg, 1824. (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - Petersburg, 1825. (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Petersburg, 1826. (Box 165, Folder 13)
    - Petersburg, 1827. (Box 165, Folder 14)
    - Petersburg, 1828. (Box 165, Folder 15)
    - Petersburg, 1829. (Box 165, Folder 16)
    - Petersburg, 1830. (Box 165, Folder 17)
    - Petersburg, 1831. (Box 165, Folder 18)
    - Petersburg, 1832. (Box 165, Folder 19)
    - Petersburg, 1833. (Box 165, Folder 20)
    - Petersburg, 1834. (Box 165, Folder 21)
    - Petersburg, 1835. (Box 165, Folder 22)
    - Petersburg, 1836. (Box 165, Folder 23)
    - Petersburg, 1837. (Box 165, Folder 24)
    - Petersburg, 1838. (Box 165, Folder 25)
    - Petersburg, 1839. (Box 165, Folder 26)
    - Petersburg, 1840. (Box 165, Folder 27)
    - Petersburg, 1841. (Box 165, Folder 28)
    - Petersburg, 1842. (Box 165, Folder 29)
    - Petersburg, 1843. (Box 165, Folder 30)
    - Petersburg, 1844. (Box 165, Folder 31)
    - Petersburg, 1845. (Box 165, Folder 32)
    - Petersburg, 1846. (Box 165, Folder 33)
    - Petersburg, 1847. (Box 165, Folder 34)
    - Petersburg, 1848. (Box 165, Folder 35)
    - Petersburg, 1849. (Box 165, Folder 36)
    - Petersburg, 1850. (Box 165, Folder 37)
    - Petersburg, 1851. (Box 165, Folder 38)
    - Petersburg, 1852. (Box 165, Folder 39)
    - Petersburg, 1853. (Box 165, Folder 40)
    - Petersburg, 1854. (Box 165, Folder 41)
    - Petersburg, 1855. (Box 165, Folder 42)
    - Petersburg, 1856. (Box 165, Folder 43)
    - Richmond, 1787. (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - Richmond, 1788. (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - Richmond, 1793. (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Richmond, 1794. (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - Richmond, 1795. (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Richmond, 1796. (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - Richmond, 1797. (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Richmond, 1798. (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - Richmond, 1799. (Box 166, Folder 9)
    - Richmond, 1800. (Box 166, Folder 10)
    - Richmond, 1801. (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Richmond, 1802. (Box 166, Folder 12)
    - Richmond, 1803. (Box 166, Folder 13)
    - Richmond, 1804. (Box 166, Folder 14)
    - Richmond, 1805. (Box 166, Folder 15)
    - Richmond, 1806. (Box 166, Folder 16)
    - Richmond, 1807. (Box 166, Folder 17)
    - Richmond, 1808. (Box 166, Folder 18)
    - Richmond, 1809. (Box 166, Folder 19)
    - Richmond, 1810. (Box 166, Folder 20)
    - Richmond, 1811. (Box 166, Folder 21)
    - Richmond, 1812. (Box 166, Folder 22)
    - Richmond, 1813. (Box 166, Folder 23)
    - Richmond, 1814. (Box 166, Folder 24)
    - Richmond, 1815. (Box 166, Folder 25)
    - Richmond, 1816. (Box 166, Folder 26)
    - Richmond, 1817. (Box 166, Folder 27)
    - Richmond, 1818. (Box 166, Folder 28)
    - Richmond, 1819. (Box 166, Folder 29)
    - Richmond, 1820. (Box 166, Folder 30)
    - Richmond, 1821. (Box 166, Folder 31)
    - Richmond, 1822. (Box 166, Folder 32)
    - Richmond, 1823. (Box 166, Folder 33)
    - Richmond, 1824. (Box 166, Folder 34)
    - Richmond, 1825. (Box 166, Folder 35)
    - Richmond, 1826. (Box 166, Folder 36)
    - Richmond, 1827. (Box 166, Folder 37)
    - Richmond, 1828. (Box 166, Folder 38)
    - Richmond, 1829. (Box 166, Folder 39)
    - Richmond, 1830. (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - Richmond, 1831. (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - Richmond, 1832. (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Richmond, 1833. (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Richmond, 1834. (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Richmond, 1835. (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Richmond, 1836. (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - Richmond, 1837. (Box 167, Folder 8)
    - Richmond, 1838. (Box 167, Folder 9)
    - Richmond, 1839. (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - Richmond, 1840. (Box 167, Folder 11)
    - Richmond, 1841. (Box 167, Folder 12)
    - Richmond, 1842. (Box 167, Folder 13)
    - Richmond, 1843. (Box 167, Folder 14)
    - Richmond, 1844. (Box 167, Folder 15)
    - Richmond, 1845. (Box 167, Folder 16)
    - Richmond, 1846. (Box 167, Folder 17)
    - Richmond, 1847. (Box 167, Folder 18)
    - Richmond, 1848. (Box 167, Folder 19)
    - Richmond, 1849. (Box 167, Folder 20)
    - Richmond, 1850. (Box 167, Folder 21)
    - Richmond, 1851. (Box 167, Folder 22)
    - Richmond, 1852. (Box 167, Folder 23)
    - Richmond, 1853. (Box 167, Folder 24)
    - Richmond, 1854. (Box 167, Folder 25)
    - Richmond, 1855. (Box 167, Folder 26)
    - Richmond, 1856. (Box 167, Folder 27)
    - Richmond, 1858. (Box 167, Folder 28)
    - Richmond, undated. (Box 167, Folder 29)
    - Roanoke, 1842. (Box 167, Folder 30)
    - Roanoke, 1843. (Box 167, Folder 31)
    - Roanoke, 1844. (Box 167, Folder 32)
    - Roanoke, 1845. (Box 167, Folder 33)
    - Roanoke, 1846. (Box 167, Folder 34)
    - Roanoke, 1847. (Box 167, Folder 35)
    - Roanoke, 1848. (Box 167, Folder 36)
    - Roanoke, 1849. (Box 167, Folder 37)
    - Roanoke, 1850. (Box 167, Folder 38)
    - Roanoke, 1851. (Box 167, Folder 39)
    - Roanoke, 1852. (Box 167, Folder 40)
    - Staunton, 1833. (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Williamsburg, 1784. (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Williamsburg, 1785. (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Williamsburg, 1786. (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Williamsburg, 1788. (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Williamsburg, 1793. (Box 168, Folder 6)
    - Williamsburg, 1794. (Box 168, Folder 7)
    - Williamsburg, 1797. (Box 168, Folder 8)
    - Williamsburg, 1798. (Box 168, Folder 9)
    - Williamsburg, 1802. (Box 168, Folder 10)
    - Williamsburg, 1803. (Box 168, Folder 11)
    - Williamsburg, 1804. (Box 168, Folder 12)
    - Williamsburg, 1805. (Box 168, Folder 13)
    - Williamsburg, 1806. (Box 168, Folder 14)
    - Williamsburg, 1807. (Box 168, Folder 15)
    - Williamsburg, 1808. (Box 168, Folder 16)
    - Williamsburg, 1809. (Box 168, Folder 17)
    - Williamsburg, 1811. (Box 168, Folder 18)
    - Williamsburg, 1812. (Box 168, Folder 19)
    - Williamsburg, 1813. (Box 168, Folder 20)
    - Williamsburg, 1814. (Box 168, Folder 21)
    - Williamsburg, 1816. (Box 168, Folder 22)
    - Williamsburg, 1818. (Box 168, Folder 23)
    - Williamsburg, 1821. (Box 168, Folder 24)
    - Williamsburg, 1823. (Box 168, Folder 25)
    - Williamsburg, 1824. (Box 168, Folder 26)
    - Williamsburg, 1826. (Box 168, Folder 27)
    - Williamsburg, 1827. (Box 168, Folder 28)
    - Williamsburg, 1828. (Box 168, Folder 29)
    - Williamsburg, 1829. (Box 168, Folder 30)
    - Williamsburg, 1831. (Box 168, Folder 31)
    - Williamsburg, 1835. (Box 168, Folder 32)
    - Williamsburg, 1837. (Box 168, Folder 33)
    - Williamsburg, 1839. (Box 168, Folder 34)
    - Williamsburg, 1840. (Box 168, Folder 35)
    - Williamsburg, 1845. (Box 168, Folder 36)
    - Williamsburg, 1849. (Box 168, Folder 37)
    - Williamsburg, no date. (Box 168, Folder 38)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1787. (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1788. (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1790. (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1792. (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1794. (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1795. (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1796. (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1797. (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1798. (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1799. (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1800. (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1801. (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1802. (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1803. (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1804. (Box 169, Folder 15)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1805. (Box 169, Folder 16)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1806. (Box 169, Folder 17)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1807. (Box 169, Folder 18)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1808. (Box 169, Folder 19)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1809. (Box 169, Folder 20)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1810. (Box 169, Folder 21)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1813. (Box 169, Folder 22)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1814. (Box 169, Folder 23)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1816. (Box 169, Folder 24)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1818. (Box 169, Folder 25)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1819. (Box 169, Folder 26)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1820. (Box 169, Folder 27)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1822. (Box 169, Folder 28)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1823. (Box 169, Folder 29)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1824. (Box 169, Folder 30)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1825. (Box 169, Folder 31)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1826. (Box 169, Folder 32)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1827. (Box 169, Folder 33)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1828. (Box 169, Folder 34)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1829. (Box 169, Folder 35)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1833. (Box 169, Folder 36)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1834. (Box 169, Folder 37)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1835. (Box 169, Folder 38)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1838. (Box 169, Folder 39)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1839. (Box 169, Folder 40)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1840. (Box 169, Folder 41)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1841. (Box 169, Folder 42)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1842. (Box 169, Folder 43)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1843. (Box 169, Folder 44)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1844. (Box 169, Folder 45)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1845. (Box 169, Folder 46)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1847. (Box 169, Folder 47)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1848. (Box 169, Folder 48)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1849. (Box 169, Folder 49)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1850. (Box 169, Folder 50)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1851. (Box 169, Folder 51)
    - No Locality Mentioned, 1852. (Box 169, Folder 52)
    - No Locality Mentioned, undated. (Box 169, Folder 53)
  - Subseries C. Resignations, 1823-1856.
    Subseries C is housed in two archival boxes (Boxes 170-171) and is arranged in chronological order. This subseries contains letters of resignation from militia officers to the adjutant general or governor between 1822 and 1856. The resignations sometimes include the commissions signed by the governor.
    Chronological.
    - Resignations, 1783. (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Resignations, 1784. (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Resignations, 1823. (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Resignations, 1824. (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Resignations, 1825. (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Resignations, 1826. (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - Resignations, 1827. (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Resignations, 1828. (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Resignations, 1829. (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Resignations, 1831. (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - Resignations, 1833. (Box 170, Folder 11)
    - Resignations, 1834. (Box 170, Folder 12)
    - Resignations, 1835. (Box 170, Folder 13)
    - Resignations, 1836. (Box 170, Folder 14)
    - Resignations, 1837. (Box 170, Folder 15)
    - Resignations, 1838. (Box 170, Folder 16)
    - Resignations, 1839. (Box 170, Folder 17)
    - Resignations, 1840. (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Resignations, 1841. (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - Resignations, 1842. (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - Resignations, 1843. (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - Resignations, 1844. (Box 171, Folder 5)
    - Resignations, 1845. (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - Resignations, 1846. (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Resignations, 1847. (Box 171, Folder 8)
    - Resignations, 1848. (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - Resignations, 1849. (Box 171, Folder 10)
    - Resignations, 1850. (Box 171, Folder 11)
    - Resignations, 1851. (Box 171, Folder 12)
    - Resignations, 1852. (Box 171, Folder 13)
    - Resignations, 1853. (Box 171, Folder 14)
    - Resignations, 1854. (Box 171, Folder 15)
    - Resignations, 1855. (Box 171, Folder 16)
    - Resignations, 1856. (Box 171, Folder 17)